Rômulo Collopy

Married, Brasilian, 35 y.o. +55 (21) 96833 0830 romulo.collopy@gmail.com https://github.com/romulocollopy Rua Farias Brito, 23, apt 104; Rio de Janeiro - RJ. Brazil. CEP: 20540-320

Web Developer specialized in Python with considerable knowledge in JavaScript, Ruby and other scripting languages. Interested in DevOps, continuous integration and agile methodologies. Currently I work in a 8 years old ecosystem, constituted of 5 applications running in Python and Ruby. We have many challenges in the infrastructure, such as integrating new features in the legacy code and serving more than 800 clients, including the operation of 15 hospitals.

Our team, although small, has managed to improve the amazon infrastructure and deploy process from a very old model based in scripts, to more imperative ways of deploy, using ansible, docker and kubernetes in some parts. We were also capable of extracting some of the old functionality to a separate service with improved architecture and up to date technology. Our error metrics lowered more than 70% and we have more reliable software.

Since I started developing, I've been focused in software maintainability, aiming to build softwares capable of being quickly evolved and changed. I tend to avoid premature optimizations and I believe the applications should be monitored and optimized in the important points.

I enjoy writing unitary and integration tests and to keep the code continuously integrated. I'm also interested in linux systems administration and DevOps tasks, always looking for better ways to ship my code.

As a former project manager I also care about the process of planning, building and delivering software in the best possible way to the company and the crew.

The position I could contribute faster to the companies is as a backend developer, specially using Python. Nevertheless I'm eager to learn new things, and I could fit in other positions if the company is able to deal with my learning curve.

Personally, I'm a team player and enjoy helping my coworkers every time I can, and -- of course -- learning from their experience. In addition to it, I use to participate of software conferences and to contribute with open source projects.

Technical knowledge

Programing Languages

Python (4y) JavaScript (4y) PHP (2y) Ruby (1y)

Frameworks

Django (3y +)
Flask (1y -)
Sanic (1y -)
AngularJS (2y +)
KnockoutJs (1y -)
Vue.js (1y -)
Google Polymer(1y-)

Databases

PostgreSQL (3y +)
MySQL / MariaDB (1y +)
sqlite (3y +)
MongoDB (1y -)

DevOps

Fabric (2y +) Ansible (1y +) Vagrant (2y +) Docker (1y -) Kubenetes (1y -)

Operating Systems

Ubuntu Server (3y +) Debian Server (1y +) CentOS Server (1y -) Arch Linux (3y +)

Professional Experience

Fullstack Developer at BR MED

07/2017 - present

Evolution and refactoring of an 8 years old ecosystem of applications, written in Python/Django and Ruby with Sinatra and Rails. Amazon AWS infrastructure update using ansible Kops, Kubernetes and Docker. Focus in Archtecture restructuration, applying Hexagonal Archtechture and Domain Driven Design.

Freelancer Backend Developer at Simple Fractal

07/2016 - 05/2017

Django Rest APIs development for various projects, frontend implementation for some, and deploy in Heroku PaaS. I've worked in a completely remote team mostly in New York and Brazil.

Consultant at LegalCloud

07/2016 - 02/2017

Software counseling for development and managing teams. Improvement of deploy process and decoupling of application to enable unit testing. Once a week consultancy.

Backend Developer at Carta (Former eShares)

02/2016 - 07/2016

Development and maintenance of Django / KnockoutJs systems; Testing legacy code and guiding to new architecture standards in a environment of about 40 developers.

Backend Developer at Parafernalia Interativa

08/2015 - 01/2016

Development and maintenance of Django / AngularJS systems; Continuous integration on Amazon Ubuntu and CentOs servers. Technical optimization in the applications. It was where I started to dig into agile methodologies, like scrum and Kamban. It also was where I could deepen my testing knowledge and apply it in a production software.

The job was semipresencial and the team was distributed.

Founder / Developer at Aos Fatos

06/2015 - present

Planning and execution of all the technological infrastructure to aosfatos.org portal, using Python/Django, vanilla JS and AngularJS. Development of a chatbot using Python/Bottery/Chatterbot. Infrastructure and DevOps implementation of all systems.

Backend developer at Icons4u

08/2014 - 07/2015

Development and maintenance of Django / AngularJS systems; manual deploy on CentOS and Debian servers. Started the automatizated tests process; Optimization of slow parts of the application; Caching Implementation.

Fullstack developer at Laboratório de Sistemas

02/2014 - 08/2014

Evolution and maintenance of vanilla PHP systems. Implementation of HTML, CSS and JS frontends. I've started as an apprentice and in 6 months I was the main responsible by a couple of projects.

Project Manager at Fundo Brasileiro para a Biodiversidade.

05/2011 - 01/2014

Managing institutional projects, specially the Ecofunds database, coordinating teams to rescue a legacy applications and rebuild it using Django Framework.

Webdesigner at ImageCare

09/2006 - 03/2007

Building websites using Flash/HTML.

Education

- Bachelor Degree in Computer Sciences at Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro (Incomplete);
- Technical License in Electricity by CEFET/RJ;
- Social Communication Bachelor Degree with a Major in Public Relations (UERJ);
- Welcome to the Django Django Web Framework;
- Objetos Pytonicos Python O.O.;
 Python pra quem sabe Python Advanced topics in Python;
- Ng-Masters AngularJS;Python Patterns Design Patterns in Python.
- Modern React with redux
- · Advanced React with Redux

Languages

- Fluent English;
- Advaced Spanish;
- · Native Portuguese.